SAI PRASHANTH CHANDRAMOULI ("SAI")

312 E Olive PI, #103, Seattle, WA 98122 | 480-703-5615 | saiprash1993@yahoo.co.in | in.linkedin.com/in/saipc | github.com/TDA

SUMMARY

Full-stack Software Development Engineer at Amazon with 3 years of experience building secure Amazon-scale web applications with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript - jQuery and ReactJS, backend services with Java, Kotlin, and serverless applications using AWS technologies - API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS, ElasticSearch.

EDUCATION

Arizona State University, Master's (Thesis) in Computer Science. GPA 3.50/4.00

May 2016

Anna University, Bachelor's in Computer Science and Engineering. GPA 4.00/4.00

Mar 2014

EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Inc., Software Development Engineer II, Compliance - Transaction Risk Management.

Dec 2017 -Present

- · Implemented a Self Service portal for non-engineers (TPM's, Product and Compliance Managers) to automatically generate the code for launching risk investigation tools to different regions and marketplaces, reducing the engineering effort from 3 weeks to 0.5 days (96% reduction in time consumed) for each new region, resulting in 3-year annualized savings of \$350,000.
- · Implemented and launched risk investigation tools in 3 new regions Amazon Payments UK, Amazon Payments Europe, and Amazon Payments India enabling 18 types of investigations for Amazon businesses to stay compliant with regulations.
- Designed and implemented clustered case support for investigating related merchants enabling investigations of up to 2800 sellers simultaneously to be conducted and filed to regulatory bodies, resulting in a savings of \$12,000 per year.
- · Migrated legacy search service to AWS ElasticSearch reducing page load times from 8 seconds to 3.4 seconds (57% reduction) and reducing hardware cost by \$6500 a year (70% reduction in cost).
- · Conducted over 250 interviews to hire Software Developers for Amazon, resulting in 82 successful hires. Currently a Bar-Raiser-in-training (BRIT) and working to ensure the quality of all new hires at Amazon.

Amazon, Inc., Software Development Engineer, Compliance - Suspicious Activity Monitoring.

Aug 2016 -Dec 2017

- Designed and implemented a pre-push hook to verify code before merging with live pipelines that reduced pipeline failures from 24 failures a month to 11 failures (54% reduction in failures) a month.
- · Implemented and launched support for Suspicious Activity monitoring, Denied Party Screening, Identity verification and TIN verification.
- Designed and implemented a Bulk report generation and download feature, reducing investigation time from 9 hours to under 6 minutes (98% reduction in time consumed) resulting in cost savings of \$30,000 per year.
- · Received "Truth Seeker" award for actively working to reduce operational cost of software.

Mozilla Corporation, Firefox Accounts Engineering Intern.

Summer 2016

- · Engineered the infrastructure for performing reverse geo-lookups to accurately detect the login location of a user, and redesigned the login emails to showcase this login history to the user (merged in Firefox-67 used by ~100 million users).
- Designed a Geolocation-based profiling mechanism to maintain login history and detect and flag anomalous logins.
- · Designed the user interface for displaying password strength to the user, with live feedback as they enter the password.

Mozilla Corporation, Cloud Services Intern.

Summer 2015

- · Designed and developed a 2-Factor Authentication system for Firefox Accounts using Node.js with Google-Authenticator, and SMS as a backup 2nd factor.
- · Implemented a Password Strength Checker for Firefox Accounts, using a Bloom Filter that maintains a list of common password hashes, that got merged in Firefox-41 (used by ~90 million users).
- · Deployed an HTML parser to scan generated HTML pages and E-Mail translations and remove malicious translations to prevent cross-site scripting vulnerabilities, in Firefox-40 train.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Java, Kotlin, XML, Sass.

AWS Technologies: Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB, ElasticSearch, SQS, SNS, Network Load Balancer.

Frameworks/Libraries: ReactJS, SemanticUI, jQuery, Bootstrap, jQueryUI, Mocha, Sinon, ESLint, Chai.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Thesis on E-Mail Header Injections - Arizona State University.

Fall 2015 - Spring

2016

Dec 2015

· Designed a black-box approach to detect E-mail Header Injection vulnerabilities in a web application.

- Developed a system to crawl the web and automatically detect E-mail Header Injection vulnerabilities.
- · Used this system to crawl 1 million forms and test them with E- mail Header Injection payloads. Discovered 673 vulnerable URLs across 296 domains.

GitChecker

- · Created a program using GitHub's API to track and analyze my coding patterns, the languages I code in, the average number of open-source projects I contribute to, the average number of lines I write, and the average amount of time I spend coding each year.
- · This allowed me to analyze which languages I feel most comfortable with and which ones I needed to focus more on. Results of this analysis can be found at: http://tda.github.io/HTMLJS-GithubAPI/.

CONFERENCE TALKS AND WORKSHOPS

Webdevcon Amsterdam 2019 - Amazon's web developer conference

Jul 2019

- · Presenting an advanced talk on using React hooks in production at Amazon to 300 Amazon developers.
- · Conducting a workshop for 120 Amazon developers on Building Serverless Applications with AWS.
- · Conducting a workshop for 120 Amazon developers on using GraphQL to build production services at Amazon.

Webdevcon Seattle 2019 - Amazon's web developer conference

May 2019

- · Presented an introductory talk on React hooks to 1500 Amazon developers to promote adoption of Hooks across Amazon.
- · Conducted a workshop for 105 Amazon developers on Building Serverless Web Applications with Native AWS.

Webdevcon Edinburgh 2018 - Amazon's web developer conference

Jul 2018

· Presented a talk on using CSS Grids in production to 160 web developers.

Zoncon Seattle 2018 - Amazon's premier security conference

May 2017

· Presented a talk to 1200 engineers on E-Mail header injections and how to prevent it in Amazon systems.